hi coach Bret contras here this is going
to be a video to show you how to find
your ideal squat depth so I'm in a power
rack here I am just going to get
my preferred squat
stance and I am going to get down as
deep as possible now you'll notice how
upright I can be cuz I'm holding on to
these supports but I can get into you
know sink as deep as I as my butt allows
so if you you can see my butt is Rock
Bottom here but come around Charles look
at my low back posture I am fully
rounded so I don't want that I am in
lumbar flexion and posterior pelvic tilt
so I'm going to use my
Erectors to tilt so now I get to where I
can tilt my pelvis and I can get to like
around a neutral posture the problem is
right now I'm still using the uprights I
would need to lean forward slightly this
is what you do in a real squat so now
I've got the pelvis tilted forward all
the way now the problem is look I'm up
on my
toes so I that's not a good squat so if
I want to be down on my pushing through
my heels I need to compromise I can't be
this deep if I come up all the way onto
my toes I can keep a strong Arch but
this is not the the way you want to
squat so where is the depth that allows
me to stay on my
heels while keeping an arch in my back
and not going into too much posterior
pelv to so go back down to my heels okay
relax get an arch push through the heels
now I kind of Tinker with here I'm not
all the way arched I come up a little
bit I come up a little bit now I'm
arched I'm fully arched
I'm pushing through my heels I'm leaning
forward like a real squat this is as
deep as I can go and still maintain good
position so this is my optimal squat
depth not here this I'm going into too
much lumbar flexion I can keep this deep
if I Rise up on my toes but that's not
ideal so the the depth that allows me my
personal Anatomy to go as deep as
possible while keeping an arch and
pushing through the heel
is right here so if I go deeper than
this I'm going to either rise up onto my
toes or round my low back so this is
just you know a few inches below
parallel I can't go you know as to Gras
like some Olympic power liers can but
it's still Deeper Than You Know Than A
lot of people so try that
drill pay attention to your lumbo pelvic
posture pay attention to you know if
you're pushing through the heels and
feeling the weight staying on your heels
and then Tinker around with your depth
to see what is optimal for you some
people um some people can't even really
make it to parallel I remember a a guy
in ockland that he would start to tilt
about right here he would start to round
he couldn't get much deeper than this it
was crazy um that's probably due to his
hip Anatomy now you can improve upon
this over time by doing by strengthening
the glutes by doing different
flexibility drills by improving ankle
dorsiflexion by improving you know hip
uh hip mobility in the hip flexors and
adductors and hip extensors but uh you
really you really your Anatomy dictates
things because there's only so much so
deep you can go depending on your the
the shape of your socket and the head of
your femur
now before I close here you can do the
same thing for deadlift de so you can
kind of get down here and round and then
from here make your shins pretty
vertical because when you actually when
the bar actually goes off the ground
you're not like this your shins are
pretty vertical so make your shins
pretty vertical here you can round relax
and now from here get an arch
okay so right here is about my
ideal this is as deep as I can squat
while keeping the
arch I can't I can't go if if if it were
much deeper than that I couldn't keep an
arched back position without having my
shins go forward so some people will do
this and they'll go like this and
they'll be rounded and they get an arch
and they're right here well this is
above where the bar would be if it was
positioned on the ground so that person
would need to do block poles or rack
poles or hex bar deadlift because with
hex bar deadlift you can let the knees
migrate forward a little bit and keep an
arch this way you can be like this but
you can't deadlift this way conventional
style anyway try those drills see if
they help you find your ideal depth
thanks for watching